Register of the Trotsky collection, 1917-1995
Hoover Institution Archives
- LEON TROTSKY SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1907-1940. (Box 14-22)
  - Discussion with Socialist Workers Party leaders on the labor party question, Coyoacan, 1938 May 31. Published in Internal Bulletin of the Socialist Workers Party Typed transcript (in English), (1938 June). (Folder 58)
  - "Meksika i britanskii imperializm," 1938 June 5. Published in El Universal Typescript (in English), (1938 June 7). (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Letter to the editor, Ken Magazine, 1938 June 28. Published in Oeuvres, Volume XVIII (Paris, Typescript (in English). Also includes cover letter by Trotsky and related letter by Joseph Hansen, 1984). (Folder 2)
  - "Eshche ob usmirenii Kronshtadta," 1938 July 6. Published in The New International Typescript (in English), (1938 August). (Folder 3)
  - "Sledstvie po delu o smerti moego syna L'va Sedova," 1938 July 19. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescripts (in Russian and English). Also includes related press release by Max Shachtman, (1938 August-September). (Folder 4)
  - "Predstoiashchii protsess diplomatov," 1938 July 24. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in English), (1938 August-September). (Folder 5)
  - Discussion with Jack Weber, Coyoacan, 1938 July 29. Published in Internal Bulletin of the Socialist Workers Party Typed transcript (in English), (1938 August). (Folder 6)
  - "Po povodu sud'by Rudol'fa Klementa," 1938 August 3. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in English), (1938 August-September). (Folder 7)
  - "SSSR i Iaponiia," 1938 August 11. Published in Socialist Appeal Typescript (in English), (1938 August 27). (Folder 8)
  - Interview with Lloyd Tupling, Coyoacan, 1938 August 12. Published in Sunday Oregonian Typed transcript (in English), (1938 September 4). (Folder 9)
  - "Sledstvie po delu o smerti L'va Sedova," 1938 August 24. Published in Socialist Appeal Typescript (in English), (1938 September 10). (Folder 10)
  - "Why Russia Is Powerless: The Totalitarian Defeatists in the Kremlin," 1938 September 12. Published in Liberty Typescript (in English), (1938 November 26). (Folder 11)
  - "Yes or No?" 1938 September 14. Published in Writings, 1937-38 (New York, Typescript (in English), 1976). (Folder 12)
  - "Navstrechu resheniiu," 1938 September 17. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian), (1938 October). (Folder 13)
  - "Frazy i real'nost'," 1938 September 19. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in English), (1938 October). (Folder 14)
  - "Totalitarnoe 'pravo ubezhishcha,'" 1938 September 19. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in English), (1938 October). (Folder 15)
  - Interview with El Pais (Havana) correspondent, Coyoacan, 1938 September 21. Published in Socialist Appeal Typescript of statements (in English), (1938 October 8). (Folder 16)
  - Interview with Mateo Fossa, Coyoacan, 1938 September 26. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typed transcript (in English). Also includes declaration of adherence to Fourth International by Fossa, (1938 October). (Folder 17)
  - Discussion with Abraham Plotkin on American trade unions, Coyoacan, 1938 September 29. Published in Socialist Appeal Typed transcript (in English), (1938 October 29). (Folder 18)
  - "Svezhii urok," 1938 October 10. Published in Workers Fight Typescript (in Russian) (Folder 19)
  - Sound recorded speech on anniversaries of the Fourth International and of the Socialist Workers Party, Coyoacan, 1938 October 10. Published in Socialist Appeal Typed transcript (in English). See also PHONORECORDS; and PHONOTAPE, (1938 November 5). (Folder 20)
  - Discussion with Socialist Workers Party leaders on the Mexican situation, Coyoacan, 1938 November 4. Published in Intercontinental Press Typed transcript (in English), (1975 May 19). (Folder 21)
  - "Novaia era mira?" 1938 November 4. Published in Hoy Typescript (in Russian), (1938 November 18). (Folder 22)
  - Discussion with Nathan Gould on the youth question, Coyoacan, 1938 November 18. Published in Writings, 1938-39 (New York, Typed transcript (in English), 1974). (Folder 23)
  - "Chas resheniia blizitsia," 1938 December 14. Published in Socialist Appeal Typescript (in English), (1938 December 24). (Folder 24)
  - "The Jewish Bourgeoisie and Revolutionary Struggle," 1938 December 22. Published in Fourth International Typescript (in English), (1945 December). (Folder 25)
  - "Declaration forcee," 1939 January 4. Published in Writings, 1938-39 (New York, Typescript (in French), 1974). (Folder 26)
  - Statement on Diego Rivera, 1939 January 11. Published in Writings, 1938-39 (New York, Typescript (in French), 1974). (Folder 27)
  - "Eks-radikal'naia intelligentsiia i mirovaia reaktsiia," 1939 January 30. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian), (1939 February). (Folder 28)
  - "Ispanskaia tragediia," 1939 January 30. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian), (1939 February). (Folder 29)
  - "Stalin, Skoblin i ko.," 1939 January 30. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian), (1939 February). (Folder 30)
  - "Za Grinshpana: Protiv fashistskikh pogromshchikov i stalinskikh negodiaev!" 1939 January 30. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian), (1939 February). (Folder 31)
  - "Zhuo i Toledano," 1939 January 30. Published in Writings, 1938-39 (New York, Typescript (in Russian), 1974). (Folder 32)
  - "Ou va le P.S.O.P.?" 1939 February 14. Published in The New International Typescript (in French), (1939 May). (Folder 33)
  - "Eshche raz o prichinakh porazheniia ispanskoi revoliutsii: Izobretateli zontika," 1939 March 4. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian), (1939 March-April). (Folder 34)
  - "Ispaniia, Stalin i Ezhov," 1939 March 4. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian), (1939 March-April). (Folder 35)
  - "Misterii imperializma," 1939 March 4. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian), (1939 March-April). (Folder 36)
  - "Umerla Krupskaia," 1939 March 4. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian), (1939 March-April). (Folder 37)
  - "Gitler i Stalin," 1939 March 6. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian), (1939 March-April). (Folder 38)
  - "Eshche o 'krizise marksizma,'" 1939 March 7. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian), (1939 March-April). (Folder 39)
  - "Shag v storonu sotsialpatriotizma," 1939 March 7. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian), (1939 March-April). (Folder 40)
  - "Uchites' rabotat' po-stalinski!" 1939 March 7. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian), (1939 March-April). (Folder 41)
  - Answers to questions of Sybil Vincent, 1939 March 18. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in English), (1939 March-April). (Folder 42)
  - Discussion with Socialist Workers Party leaders on work in the Communist Party, Coyoacan, 1939 March 20. Published in Writings, 1938-39 (New York, Typed and mimeograph transcripts (in English), 1974). (Folder 43)
  - Discussion with C. L. R. James on the Fourth International in Europe, Coyoacan, 1939 April. Published in Internal Bulletin of the Socialist Workers Party Typed transcript (in English), (1939 March 20). (Folder 44)
  - Discussions with Socialist Workers Party leaders on the race question in the United States, Coyoacan, 1939 April 4-5. Published in Internal Bulletin of the Socialist Workers Party Typed transcripts (in English), (1939 June). (Folder 45)
  - Discussion with Socialist Workers Party leaders on the race question in the United States, Coyoacan, 1939 April 11. Published in Internal Bulletin of the Socialist Workers Party Typed transcript (in English), (1939 June). (Folder 46)
  - "Bonapartistskaia filosofiia gosudarstva," 1939 May 1. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian), (1939 May-July). (Folder 47)
  - "Nationalized Industry and Workers' Management," 1939 May 12. Published in Fourth International (1946 August). Printed copy (in Spanish, in Programa, 1952 May) (Folder 48)
  - "Istoriia bol'shevizma v zerkale Tsentral'nogo Komiteta," 1939 June 7. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian), (1939 May-July). (Folder 49)
  - "Moralisty i sikofanty protiv marksizma," 1939 June 9. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian), (1939 May-July). (Folder 50)
  - "Desiat' let," 1939 June 10. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian), (1939 May-July). (Folder 51)
  - "K itogam chistok," 1939 June 10. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian), (1939 May-July). (Folder 52)
  - "Lenin o stalintsakh," 1939 June 10. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian), (1939 May-July). (Folder 53)
  - "Prognozy 1931 g.," 1939 June 10. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian), (1939 May-July). (Folder 54)
  - "Sovetskie plutarkhi," 1939 June 10. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian), (1939 May-July). (Folder 55)
  - "1917 g.-1939 g.," 1939 June 10. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian), (1939 May-July). (Folder 56)
  - "'Trotskizm' i PSOP," 1939 July 15. Published in Juin 36 Typescript (in Russian), (1939 September 10). (Folder 57)
  - "'Progressivnyi paralich,'" 1939 July 29. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian), (1939 August-October). (Folder 58)
  - "Nezavisimost' Ukrainy i sektanskaia putanitsa," 1939 July 30. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian), (1939 August-October). (Folder 59)
  - "Stalin," 1939 September 22. Published in Life (1939 October 2). Printed copy (in English, in Life (Folder 60)
  - "SSSR v voine," 1939 September 25. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian), and typed excerpts (in English), (1939 August-October). (Folder 61)
  - "Eshche i eshche raz o prirode SSSR," 1939 October 18. Published in Internal Bulletin of the Socialist Workers Party Typescript (in Russian), (1939 November 6). (Folder 62)
  - "K voprosu o rabochei samooborone," 1939 October 25. Published in Writings, 1939-40 (New York, Typescript (in Russian), 1973). (Folder 63)
  - Prospectus of article for Liberty magazine, 1939 November 15. Published in Writings: Supplement, 1934-40 (New York, Typescript (in English), 1979). (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - "Dvoinaia zvezda: Gitler-Stalin," 1939 December 4. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii, (1940 January)
    - Typescript (in English) (Folder 2)
    - Printed copy (in English, in Liberty, 1940 January 27) (Folder 3)
  - "Melko-burzhuaznaia oppozitsiia v Rabochei Sotsialisticheskoi Partii Soedinennykh Shtatov," 1939 December 15. Published in Internal Bulletin of the Socialist Workers Party Typescript (in English), (1940 January). (Folder 4)
  - Letter to the editor, Excelsior, 1939 December 26. Published in Writings: Supplement, 1934-40 (New York, Typescript (in Spanish), 1979). (Folder 5)
  - Notes on dialectics, Holograph and typescripts (in Russian). Also includes a few clippings used as working materials, 1939-1940. (Folder 6)
  - Draft article on war for Liberty, 1940. Holograph and typescripts (in Russian and English). Also includes issue of Novoe russkoe slovo used as working material (Folder 7)
  - Notes, fragments, and working materials, Holographs and typescripts (in Russian and French), 1940. (Folder 8)
  - Stalin, 1940. Published in New York, 1941. See also SUBJECT FILE/Trotsky, Leon/ Stalin
    - Typescript (incomplete, in Russian) (Folder 9-10)
    - Photocopy of typescript (in Russian) (Folder 11-12)
    - Photocopy of typescript appendix, "Tri kontseptsii russkoi revoliutsii" (in Russian) (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Research materials assembled by John G. Wright in New York and sent to Trotsky. Also includes several accompanying letters from Wright to Trotsky or his secretaries, and one related letter from Jean van Heijenoort to Wright, 1939, 1937-1939 (Folder 2)
  - "Ot tsarapiny k opasnosti gangreny," 1940 January 24. Published in Internal Bulletin of the Socialist Workers Party Typescript (in Russian), (1940 February). (Folder 3)
  - Testament, 1940 February 27. Published in Trotsky's Diary in Exile, 1935 (Cambridge, Mass., Holograph copy (in Russian), and typescript (in English). Also includes related letters by Joseph Hansen, 1958). (Folder 4)
  - Preface to a proposed book, 1940 April. Published in Intercontinental Press Typescript (in Russian), (1970 July 2). (Folder 5)
  - "Melkoburzhuaznye moralisty i proletarskaia partiia," 1940 April 23. Published in In Defense of Marxism (New York, Typescript (in Russian), 1942). (Folder 6)
  - "Vas obmanyvaiut! Pis'mo v SSSR," 1940 April 23. Published in Socialist Appeal Typescripts (in Russian and English), (1940 May 11). (Folder 7)
  - "Itogi Finliandskogo opyta," 1940 April 25. Published in Clave Typescript (in Russian), (1940 April-May). (Folder 8)
  - Fragment on the future of Hitler's armies, ca. 1940 May. Published in The Militant Typescript (in Russian), (1941 May 10). (Folder 9)
  - "Imperialistskaia voina i proletarskaia revoliutsiia: Manifest Chetvertogo Internatsionala," 1940 May 26. Published in Socialist Appeal Typescript (in Russian), (1940 June 29). (Folder 10)
  - "Sobre Lombardo Toledano" and "Sobre Robert Sheldon," Typescript (in Spanish), 1940 June 6. (Folder 11)
  - "Pokushenie 24-go maia," 1940 June 8. Published in Fourth International Typescript (in Russian), (1940 October). (Folder 12)
  - Discussions with Socialist Workers Party leaders, Coyoacan, 1940 June 12-15. Published in Internal Bulletin of the Socialist Workers Party Typed transcripts (in English), (1940 August-September). (Folder 13)
  - "Rol' Kremlia v evropeiskoi katastrofe," 1940 June 18. Published in Socialist Appeal Typescript (in Russian), (1940 June 22). (Folder 14)
  - "Chto dal'she? My ne meniaem kursa," 1940 June 27. Published in Socialist Appeal Typescript (in Russian), (1940 July 6). (Folder 15)
  - "Evreiskii vopros," 1940 July. Published in Fourth International Typescript (in Russian). Also includes clipping used as research material, (1945 December). (Folder 16)
  - Preface to O-kuo ko ming shih (Chinese edition of Istoriia russkoi revoliutsii), Published in Shanghai, 1940. Typescript (in Russian), 1940 July. (Folder 17)
  - Writing on Futuro, El Popular and La Voz de Mexico as agents of the G.P.U., Typescript (in Russian), 1940 July. (Folder 18)
  - "El Senor Pavon Flores como abogado de la G.P.U.," Typescript (in Spanish), 1940 July 3. (Folder 19)
  - " Futuro, El Popular, La Voz de Mexico y los agentes de la G.P.U.," 1940 July 5. Published in Los Gangsters de Stalin (Mexico City, Typescript (in Spanish) (Folder 20)
  - Discussion with Socialist Workers Party leaders, Coyoacan, 1940 August 7. Published in Writings, 1939-40 (New York, Typed transcript (in English), 1973). (Folder 21)
  - "Komintern i GPU," 1940 August 17. Published in Fourth International, (1940 November)
    - Typescript (in Russian) (Folder 22)
    - Typescript (in Spanish) (Folder 23)
  - "Bonapartizm, fashizm i voina," 1940 August 20. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian), (1940 August-October). (Folder 24)
  - "The Class, the Party, and the Leadership: Why Was the Spanish Proletariat Defeated? Questions of Marxist Theory," 1940 August 20. Published in Fourth International Typescript with handwritten additions (in Russian), and printed copy (in English, in pamphlet form with same title, London, 1957), (1940 December). (Folder 25)
  - "O professional'nykh soiuzakh v epokhu imperialistskogo zagnivaniia," 1940 August 20. Published in Fourth International Typescripts with handwritten additions (in Russian and English), (1941 February). (Folder 26)
- NEW YORK/COYOACAN FILE, 1931-1941 (Box 23-25)
  Correspondence among associates of Leon Trotsky, primarily between Socialist Workers Party leaders in New York and secretaries and guards of Trotsky in Coyoacan. Includes some memoranda, notes, reports, statements, and financial accounts. A small amount of the material dates before the arrival of Trotsky in Mexico. Much of it relates to efforts to safeguard Trotsky and to the investigation of his assassination. Does not include writings by or correspondence of Trotsky. Arranged chronologically.
  - Letters, resolutions, theses, receipts, memorandum, and clippings. Includes letters by Sara Weber and Erwin Wolf; clippings about Wolf; resolutions and theses on the French and German sections of the International Communist League; memorandum on anti-militarist work in preparation for discussion with Trotsky; and analysis of the assassination of Sergei Kirov, 1931-1936. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - 1937
    - Letters, telegram and memoranda. Includes letters by Jan Frankel, Walter Held, George Novack, Max Shachtman, Jean van Heijenoort, Erwin Wolf, Bernard Wolfe, and John G. Wright; and memoranda on the German section of the International Communist League, January-June. (Folder 2)
    - Letters. Includes letters by James P. Cannon, Raya Dunayevskaya, Jan Frankel, Joseph Hansen, Francis Heisler, Rose Karsner, Max Shachtman, Jean van Heijenoort, Sara Weber, Bernard Wolfe, and John G. Wright, July-December. (Folder 3)
  - 1938
    - Letters, telegrams, memorandum, and report. Includes letters by Raya Dunayevskaya, Jan Frankel, Joseph Hansen, Henry Schultz, Jean van Heijenoort, and John G. Wright; report on the German section of the International Communist League; and memorandum by Jan Frankel on Maurice Parijanine, January-March. (Folder 4)
    - Letters, telegrams, reports, circulars, notes, and clippings. Includes letters by James P. Cannon, Lillian Curtiss, Raya Dunayevskaya, Jan Frankel, Joseph Hansen, Henry Schultz, Jean van Heijenoort, and Sara Weber; notes and clippings describing George Mink; reports on the Miller case; and circulars on the right of asylum, April-July. (Folder 5)
    - Letters, telegram, agreements, statement, list, and addresses. Includes letters by James P. Cannon, Lillian Curtiss, Albert Goldman, Joseph Hansen, Vaughan T. O'Brien, Henry Schultz, and Sara Weber; agreement for receipt of papers from Jeanne Martin; and draft statement for Mexican teachers in defense of Trotsky, August-December. (Folder 6)
  - 1939
    - Letters, telegram, memoranda, minutes, and press release. Includes letters by James P. Cannon, Lillian Curtiss, Raya Dunayevskaya, Fourth International Mexican Section, Joseph Hansen, Vaughan T. O'Brien, Walter O'Rourke, Henry Schultz, and Jean van Heijenoort; memoranda by Charles Curtiss on Diego Rivera; press release on interview request by H. R. Knickerbocker; and excerpt from Socialist Workers Party Political Committee minutes on assignment of Joseph Hansen to Coyoacan, January-March. (Folder 7)
    - Letters, telegram, and notes. Includes letters by James P. Cannon, Charles Curtiss, Lillian Curtiss, Vaughan T. O'Brien, and Jean van Heijenoort; and memorandum by C. L. R. James in preparation for discussion with Trotsky on race question in the United States, April-June. (Folder 8)
    - Letters and telegrams. Includes letters by James P. Cannon, Charles Cornell, Vaughan T. O'Brien, Max Shachtman, and Jean van Heijenoort, July-September. (Folder 9)
    - Letters and telegram. Includes letters by James P. Cannon, Charles Cornell, Albert Goldman, Joseph Hansen, Dwight Macdonald, Jean van Heijenoort, and John Wheelwright, October-December. (Folder 10)
  - 1940
    - General
      - Defense Fund (including Guard Fund), Coyoacan. Accounts of receipts and expenditures (Folder 11)
      - Assassination attempt Notes of telephone conversations transmitting news of attempt to New York; Socialist Workers Party reports based on accounts of guards, including diagram; summary of press conference by Trotsky; Socialist Workers Party defense fund appeal; and press releases relating to arrests in connection with attempt, (May 24). (Folder 12)
      - Assassination Notes of telephone conversations transmitting news of assassination to New York; notes on arrangements to be made following assassination; and press releases in New York and Mexico City following assassination and death of Trotsky. See also SUBJECT FILE/Trotsky, Leon/Assassination, (August 20). (Folder 13)
      - Assassination investigation
        - General. Memoranda, notes, press releases, summaries of press stories, and list of questions for witnesses (Box 24, Folder 1)
        - Ageloff, Sylvia, Hilda and Ruth. Summaries of statements by Sylvia Ageloff as reported in press; typed copy of letter from Sylvia to Hilda Ageloff; and typed reports of conversations with Hilda and Ruth Ageloff (Folder 2)
        - Chambers, Whittaker. Typed report of conversation with Whittaker Chambers (Folder 3)
        - Geltman, Emanuel, and Karsner, Walta. Typed statements by Emanuel Geltman and Walta Karsner; and typed reports of conversations with Geltman (Folder 4)
        - Mercader, Ramon. Typed copy of letter found on person of Ramon Mercader at time of assassination; typed copies of letters and telegrams from Mercader to Sylvia Ageloff; and summaries of statements by and interrogations of Mercader as reported in press (Folder 5)
        - Rosmer, Alfred and Marguerite. Typed reports of conversations with Alfred and Marguerite Rosmer (Folder 6)
        - Schultz, Henry and Dorothy. Typed statements by Henry and Dorothy Schultz (Folder 7)
      - Condolences. Letters, telegrams, and typed copies of letters and telegrams, of condolence, sent to Nataliia Sedova Trotskaia or to Socialist Workers Party (Folder 8)
      - Memorial meetings. Letters, telegrams, press releases, and announcements, relating to memorial meetings for Leon Trotsky. Includes letters by James P. Cannon, Joseph Carter, Farrell Dobbs, and Max Shachtman; speech by Albert Goldman at Mexico City meeting; typed report of Mexico City meeting; and agenda of New York City meeting (Folder 9)
    - Letters and telegram. Includes letters by Alexander Buchman, James P. Cannon, Charles Cornell, Farrell Dobbs, Albert Goldman, Walter O'Rourke, Harold Robins, Jean van Heijenoort, Sara Weber, and John G. Wright, January-May. (Folder 10)
    - June. Letters and telegrams. Includes letters by Adams, William Bryan, James P. Cannon, Charles Cornell, Farrell Dobbs, Albert Goldman, Joseph Hansen, Walter O'Rourke, Harold Robins, and Henry Schultz (Folder 11)
    - July. Letters. Includes letters by Adams, William Bryan, Alexander Buchman, Charles Cornell, Farrell Dobbs, Vincent Dunne, Albert Goldman, Joseph Hansen, and Harold Robins (Folder 12)
    - Letters, telegrams, and notes. Includes letters by Adams, William Bryan, James P. Cannon, Charles Cornell, Farrell Dobbs, Albert Goldman, and Joseph Hansen, August 1-20. (Folder 13)
    - Letters, telegrams, memorandum, and note. Includes letters by Alexander Buchman, James P. Cannon, Farrell Dobbs, Albert Goldman, Isaac Don Levine, Charles Malamuth, and Walter O'Rourke, August 21-31. (Folder 14)
    - September. Letters and telegrams. Includes letters by James P. Cannon, Farrell Dobbs, Albert Goldman, Joseph Hansen, Felix Morrow, Walter O'Rourke, and Harold Robins (Folder 15)
    - October. Letters, memorandum, and typed excerpt from press. Includes letters by James P. Cannon, Charles Cornell, Charles Curtiss, Farrell Dobbs, Albert Goldman, and Joseph Hansen; and memorandum by Albert Goldman on Nataliia Sedova Trotskaia (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Letters and telegram. Includes letters by James P. Cannon, Farrell Dobbs, Liliia Estrina, Albert Goldman, and Walter O'Rourke, November-December. (Folder 2)
  - Letters. Includes letters by Albert Goldman and Walter O'Rourke; mimeograph open letter in defense of David Alfaro Siqueiros, and mimeograph draft open letter initiated by Socialist Workers Party in response, 1941. (Folder 3)
- DEWEY COMMISSION FILE, 1936-1938. (Box 25-26)